Jorge Fioranelli

Engineering Leadership

US Visa Holder (E3)



Tech senior leader with more than 20 years of experience in the industry. Focused on company culture, scaling great teams, mentoring leaders and achieving technical excellence. Strong in system scalability, cloud computing, distributed systems and functional programming.

Professional Experience



Director of EngineeringJet.com & Walmart Labs

Sep 2015 – Present New Jersey, USA



- Head of 5 high-performance engineering teams (40+ people) across 3 locations: New York, Dublin and Bangalore
- Strong culture of technical excellence, mentoring and high productivity
- Cloud, Continuous Delivery, Functional Programming, Domain-Driven Design, Event-Driven Architecture, CQRS and Event Sourcing



Lead Consultant

Readify

Apr 2010 – Sep 2015 Sydney, Australia

- Leader of multiple consulting teams
- Microsoft Australia Engineer (Microsoft Software Development Center)
- Domain-Driven Design, Distributed Systems, Continuous Integration, Event Sourcing, Performance Analysis



Engineering Manager

Lagash Systems

Feb 2006 – Mar 2010 Buenos Aires, Argentina

- Head of 2 agile teams (15+ people)
- Architecture & Project Management
- Microsoft Argentina Consultant (Microsoft Consulting Services)
- Domain-Driven Design, Performance Analysis, Continuous Integration



Senior Software Developer

Accenture

Jan 2003 – Feb 2006 Buenos Aires, Argentina

- Hands-on Tech Lead of a small team (3 engineers)
- Architecture, Design Patterns and Performance Analysis



Software Developer AutoTrader

Feb 1999 – Jan 2003

Buenos Aires, Argentina

- Development of a classified ads web application
- Development of a magazine management system

Education

Master of Business Administration

2019 | University of Illinois

BS Computer Engineering

2003 | UADE

Skills

Engineering Leadership
Engineering Management
Cloud Computing
Microservices
Distributed Systems
Functional Programming
Domain-Driven Design
Event-Driven Architecture

Courses & Certifications

Predictive Analytics and Data Mining
Implementing Domain-Driven Design
Principles of Reactive Programming
Principles of Functional Programming
Story Value Mapping
Continuous Delivery
Command Query Responsibility Segregation
Event Sourcing
Advanced Distributed Systems Design
Professional Scrum Master
Certified Scrum Master
Value Stream Mapping
TDD Randori

Public Speaking Events

2019 | openfsharp.org | SF, US

2018 | openfsharp.org | SF, US

2016 | skillsmatter.com | London, UK

2016 | composeconference.org | NY, US

2015 | yowconference.com | Perth, AU

2015 | anzcoders.com | Sydney, AU

2014 | dddmelbourne.com | Melbourne, AU

Publications

engineeringladders.com fsharpworkshop.com fsharpreactivepatterns.com